kaki narase sonzai wo
rock away your existence
koko ni iru to
shouting that you are here
arata na tabi ga ima hajimaru
a new journey begins now
kawari yuku kisetsu no naka wo ikinuku tabi ni bokura
as we survived through the changing seasons
chie to tsuyosa wo te ni ireta kedo JUST LOOKS LIKE SURVIVAL GAME
we gained knowledge and strength (just looks like a survival game)
nagareteku jikan no naka ni
but the forgotten memories
okizari ni shita omoi wo
of the feelings abandoned within the flows of time
wasureta koto sura wasurete ita
have also been lost
kuzure kaketa toki kodoku wo shitte
when sinking down we learned loneliness
deaeta bokura hitori ja nai
but now we've met each other we are no longer alone
sarake dase kanjou wo banjou no omoi wo
unveil your feelings those high emotions
namidame ga unmei wo kaete yuku
those tears will change your fate
yami ni uchi narase kodou wo
pound your heartbeat against the darkness
kitto aeru yo onaji itami no hata no moto de
we're sure to meet under the same flag of pain
So, it's a case of not being able to fight
with the leader
unless I defeat the underlings?
Well, then...
Clash of Tears!
Hot-Blooded Master-Disciple Battle
So, you think you've blackened the path
to this Might Guy's tomorrow with this?
Youth is breaking through
the walls that close you in.
If you have both passion and effort,
then nothing is impossible!
With our sights trained on tomorrow!
Is there no tomorrow for us?
So, this wood retains
its incredible strength
because it is reinforced
and connected by Chakra, I see.
Guy-sensei.
Yagura?
Are you all right?!
I'm not Yagura.
Eldest of the three Ryudouin brothers,
Gensho!
Second son of the same, Rokkaku!
Third son, Jako!
Ryudouin?
I think I've heard of that somewhere.
Don't tell me that you don't remember!
Our father, Ryudouin Agira,
was deeply injured
by the cowardly strategies
of your Hidden Leaf Shinobi.
And unable to execute his missions,
he passed away in despair.
Our father resented you to the very end,
even muttering your name
on his deathbed...
telling us to fight
with Might Guy of Hidden Leaf Village.
From that day forth,
our objective has been
to avenge his death!
Yes! We have been lying in wait
for the time to get even with you!
Do you mean that Agira?!
There's no way I could forget that battle.
Although we were enemies
on our missions, Agira was a fine man.
That will remain in my memory
as a splendid contest, even within
the annals
of the complete eight-volume
Might Guy's History of Famous Battles.
It was a man-to-man fight.
Nothing happened that dishonoured
my Way of Ninja!
You three must be mistaken.
I won't be angry at you,
so let me out of here!
Fool! I shall wreak vengeance
upon you to settle my father's score.
I'll finish you off!
Sakura,
I noticed you were there some time ago.
My master told me to make sure
you don't overdo it.
You're hiding something, aren't you?!
No... Nothing!
Sakura, you're not very good at lying.
What?
Die, Might Guy! Enemy of our father!
Wait, I tell you!
Hey, you Yagura imposter,
infiltrating Village Hidden in the Leaves,
what are you scheming?!
Byakugan!
Guy is in that building! The building is
controlled by their Chakra!
Why you...
Intense Brow Sensei,
I'm coming to your rescue!
What is this?!
Do you intend to shut us in
with these pieces of wood?
— Don't underestimate us!
— Stop it, Naruto!
Wooden Dummies for training?
Are these also controlled by those three?
However strong they are,
they couldn't move all
of these Wooden Dummies at once.
It's hard to believe those three would
have that much power.
Byakugan!
I see.
They have a simple mechanism,
and their movements are controlled
by the labels on the back of their heads.
So, they're not moved with Puppet Jutsu?
No, they're only designed
for repeated punches and kicks,
so they probably cannot respond
to our movements!
Does this mean their movements can
be halted by removing the labels?
So, that's what it's all about!
If that's the case,
then I'll return that blow!
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Here goes!
Once I know the weak spot,
you're all mine!
— Gotcha!
This is easy!
These Wooden Dummies are
just one small part of our Jutsu!
Ninja Art:
Wooden Dummy Manipulation Jutsu!
Damn you!
Keep your wits about you!
There's one that moves differently
from the others!
Neji!
U-zu-ma-ki...
Naruto Barra...!
Stay back!
Some of these Wooden Dummies seem
to be manipulated by the Puppet Jutsu.
Be careful!
— Lee!
— Bushy Brow!
Leaf Hurricane!
Lee?!
How did you know we were here?!
From what Sakura told us,
I felt certain
that Guy-sensei would take this route
if he were headed
for the Land of Mountain Streams.
And where is Guy-sensei?
Inside there.
— What?
— Are they running away?
What's happening?!
It's just like a castle!
Leave this to me!
Guy-sensei is my master!
I would risk my life to save him!
But, Bushy Brow,
your leg injury hasn't healed yet.
I'm going in!
It's reckless!
Do you intend to interfere?
Today, I am just a bit different
from usual...!
Bushy Brow, we'll cover you.
There is a weak point in the Chakra
at the center of the castle.
If you hit there, then...
But it may be a trap!
Everyone... if it is a trap,
let's try falling into it intentionally.
Over there!
Dynamic Entry!
As we suspected,
it was a trap to lure me in.
Anyway, let's follow it through.
Rokkaku, Jako, leave the rest to me.
All right.
Take revenge on that coward
by a suitable method.
Leave it to me.
Wooden Dummy: Possess:
Transfer: Repossess Jutsu!
A Wooden Dummy here, too?
Your teacher is an incredible liar, Lee.
Is that Yagura's voice I hear?
I'll teach you both, master and student,
that sometimes passion
and effort alone come to naught.
I won't allow you to speak ill
of my teacher.
If you've got something to say,
then why don't you come out here
and say it?
There is no need.
I can amply prove it with the Wooden Dummy
that is my incarnation.
I have come to rescue my teacher!
There's no way
I'm going to let myself lose to you!
You make me laugh.
What's this? The Leaf Hurricane...?
Does this mean that the technique
I deployed that time
has been completely imitated
and mastered by Yagura?!
In that case...
Leaf's Severe Hurricane!
Can this really be Yagura?
If he's mastered not
only offensive moves,
but also learned to guard
with such perfection,
then he truly must be a genius!
What an incredibly powerful spinning kick.
The Gensho I faced off with
in the practice hall
did not have this much power.
To my knowledge,
there is only one person
who could let loose this powerful a kick.
They are student and teacher
who respect each other.
Dying fighting each other must be
a wish come true.
We'll have them crush each other
with Wooden Dummies mimicking
each other's movements.
Even if each were to discover
the true identity of his opponent...
They can't escape from the confrontation
without defeating
the Wooden Dummies before their eyes.
That is the secret
of Wooden Dummy: Possess:
Transfer: Repossess Jutsu!
Looks like my legs can't last
for very long.
If it comes to this,
there's only one move left.
Guy-sensei, it's okay, right?
If I use it for your sake,
you'll probably forgive me.
The Lotus?
Could it be that the one who is
controlling this Wooden Dummy is Lee?
Dancing Leaf Shadow!
A combo move from the Lotus Hit Back
to aerial Severe Leaf Hurricanes!
It's magnificent. Too magnificent!
Only Guy-sensei could use
such artful techniques!
Splendid! If I had not been his opponent,
I'm 100 percent certain that he would have
toppled the opponent with that Lotus.
But, at this rate,
I won't be able to beat this Jutsu.
Wait! There is a way.
That tapping is Morse Code.
"You and I are destroying each other."
But there's no way for either
of us to end this fight
without defeating the enemy's Jutsu.
So, it was Guy-sensei
that I was fighting all along?
We must both create an attack
with speed and power
of a magnitude that cannot be reproduced
by the Wooden Dummies.
"But I cannot show to you
the abyss of death again!"
Master Guy, if I do it to protect
the person who is most important to me...
"You will forgive me
for using that move, won't you?"
To me... To me...
"To me, there is no one more important
than Guy-sensei," you say?
Lee! What do you mean
by making me cry at a time like this?
Lee! I haven't forgotten the promise
I made to you back then!
"If you die... I shall die with you."
Thank you, Guy-sensei!
Now is the very time when...
One's own Way of Ninja...
— must be followed to the very end!
— Must be followed to the very end!
Third Gate: Gate of Life... Open!
Fourth Gate: Gate of Pain... Open!
Guy-sensei!
We're far from finished!
What's wrong, Elder Brother?
They're fast. They're both too fast.
At this rate,
the Wooden Dummies will... break.
Fifth Gate: Gate of Closing!
Open!
I can't see them.
They're faster than even sound!
There you go, Lee!
Bring the Chakra of your passions
to bear upon your opponent!
Right!
— The castle is...
— Crumbling?
If this was revenge,
then why did you not come at me
with the kung fu techniques of Ryudoin?
That day, though he was
the only man left,
your father refused to surrender,
but fairly and sportingly confronted me
with kung fu.
Out of respect to your father,
I faced him one-on-one.
When the fight was finished,
your father smiled slightly,
as if satisfied,
and said he would like to fight again.
Whether or not you believe me,
this is all there was to it.
Could it be
that what Father wanted to say
was not that he wanted us
to defeat Master Guy,
but that he wanted to fight again,
fair and square?
Have we had the wrong idea all along?
I learned something important
from your father in that fight.
It is not the people born
with natural gifts who are the lucky ones.
The truly fortunate are they who,
believing in themselves to the very end,
can go on striving and keep the flame
of their passions alive because of it.
That's
a good teacher-student relationship.
Naruto!
Say, Sakura! Hurry up and get Bushy Brow
to Grandma's place, will you?
Got it! Get him to the stretcher.
No, don't worry about me.
I'm okay. See to Yagura first.
Speaking of which, I still haven't asked
for Yagura's real name.
Lee, there'll be plenty of time
for that later.
Administering first-aid should
take priority.
Yes! Guy-sensei!
Yup, yup. That is really one
super teacher-student relationship.
I wish mine was as good.
hoshikuzu suchasucha sucha odoru
on a checkerboard night
ichimatsu no yoru ni
when the stardust's are rapidly dancing
aa mada kaeri takunai to kuchi ni wa dasenai naa
I just can't come out and say, "ah, I don't want to go home yet"
omowa seburi terii
suggestively
aisubeki kao ni tsuba wo misutaa kuriketto
spat at that beloved face, mister cricket
asekusai suteeji no ue de hikaru toronboon no
the trombone gradually going off-key
picchi ga dandan hazureteitteiru no mo kininaru kedo
while on the sweaty center stage does bug me
sonna koto yori kono nai mune no moyamoya wa sakki
but more importantly, the fuzziness I feel in my undeveloped chest,
nonda koora no sei kashira nee
I wonder If it's from that coke I just drank?
Yo, Kiba, Neji!
As always, you have
no sense for tension.
— What was that?!
— Be quiet, you guys.
That's right. They are about to
give us important instructions.
— Okay...
— Choji too! Can't you eat a little later?
— I don't mind.
— That's not the point at all!
N-Naruto... Um... I...
Things are heating up in here,
aren't they, Sakura?
You are getting too excited.
Hey. We're all here.
Then, I'll explain the next mission.
Next time:
"A Tough Pinch! The Konoha 11 All Gather."